# Tzu-Sheng Kuo

(650) 391-5684tskuo@stanford.edutskuo.github.io

I create interactive systems that envision or reshape the design of future technology to support human well-being. My research interest in human-computer interaction is at the intersection of digital fabrication, sensing and interaction techniques, and applications to digital healthcare, behavior change, and accessibility.

#### Education

2019 - Jun 2021 Stanford University.

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering, GPA: 4.00/4.00

2014 - 2019 National Taiwan University (NTU).

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering, GPA: 4.25/4.30, Summa Cum Laude (Top 1%)

## Research Experience

## **Human-Computer Interaction**

2019 - Present Stanford HCl Group, Stanford, CA.

Advisors: Prof. James Landay, Prof. Elizabeth Murnane

- o Proposed a design framework for interactive systems that adopt natural elements to support user well-being
- o Resulted in one publication in submission to CHI 2021
- 2017 2019 Interactive Graphics Lab, NTU, Taiwan.

Advisors: Prof. Bing-Yu Chen, Prof. Xing-Dong Yang

- o Designed two pneumatic interfaces that emulate physical objects to provide haptic feedback in VR
- o Designed a software tool with an autocomplete feature to assist makers in building breadboard circuits
- o Resulted in three publications at UIST 2018, UIST 2019, and CHI 2019

## Computer Vision & Machine Learning

2017 - 2019 Vision and Learning Lab, NTU, Taiwan.

Advisor: Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang

- o Modified DeepLabv3+ and proposed a loss function for semantic segmentation on satellite imagery
- o Resulted in one publication at DeepGlobe Workshop in CVPR 2018

#### Signal Processing

2016 - 2019 Multimedia Processing and Communications Lab, NTU, Taiwan.

Advisor: Prof. Homer H. Chen

- o Approximated the temporal variation of gaze fixation to estimate the depth map of indoor spaces based on eye vergence
- o Resulted in one publication at ICIP 2018

## Peer-Reviewed Publications

CHI 2021 **Tzu-Sheng Kuo**, Kelsey Wang, Sarah L. Billington, James A. Landay, and Elizabeth L. Murnane. 2021. Biophilic Technology: Exploring the Application of Biophilic Principles to the Design of Digital Interfaces. In Submission to *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI '21). ACM, New York, NY, USA. [under review]

UIST 2019 Shan-Yuan Teng, Cheng-Lung Lin, Chi-huan Chiang, Tzu-Sheng Kuo, Liwei Chan, Da-Yuan Huang, and Bing-Yu Chen.

2019. TilePoP: Tile-type Pop-up Prop for Virtual Reality. In *Proceedings of the 32nd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology* (UIST '19). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 639–649.

**Best Paper Honorable Mention [PDF]** 

 $CHI\ 2019\quad Jo-Yu\ Lo,\ Da-Yuan\ Huang,\ \textbf{Tzu-Sheng}\ \textbf{Kuo},\ Chen-Kuo\ Sun,\ Jun\ Gong,\ Teddy\ Seyed,\ Xing-Dong\ Yang,\ and\ Bing-Yu\ Chen.$ 

2019. AutoFritz: Autocomplete for Prototyping Virtual Breadboard Circuits. In *Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI '19). ACM, New York, NY, USA, Paper 403, 1–13.

Best Paper Honorable Mention [PDF]

UIST 2018 Shan-Yuan Teng, **Tzu-Sheng Kuo**, Chi Wang, Chi-huan Chiang, Da-Yuan Huang, Liwei Chan, and Bing-Yu Chen. 2018. PuPoP: Pop-up Prop on Palm for Virtual Reality. In *Proceedings of the 31st Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology* (UIST '18). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 5–17. [PDF]

CVPRW 2018 **Tzu-Sheng Kuo**\*, Keng-Sen Tseng\*, Jia-Wei Yan\*, Yen-Cheng Liu, and Yu-Chiang Frank Wang. 2018. Deep Aggregation Net for Land Cover Classification. In *IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Workshops* (CVPRW '18). Salt Lake City, UT, pp. 252–256. \*The authors contributed equally. [PDF]

ICIP 2018 **Tzu-Sheng Kuo**, Kuang-Tsu Shih, Sheng-Lung Chung, and Homer H. Chen. 2018. Depth from Gaze. In 25th IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP '18). Athens, pp. 2910–2914. [PDF]

## Posters and Demos

UIST 2020 **Tzu-Sheng Kuo** and Eric Rawn. 2020. Let It Rip! Using Velcro for Acoustic Labeling. In *The Adjunct Publication of the* 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST '20). [PDF]

(a project mentored by Prof. Michael Bernstein at Stanford)

HCOMP 2020 Tzu-Sheng Kuo, McArdle Hankin, Miranda Li, Andrew Ying, and Cathy Wang. 2020. Assessing Political Bias using

• Crowdsourced Pairwise Comparisons. In *Proceeding of the 8th AAAI Conference on Human Computation and Crowdsourcing* (HCOMP '20). [PDF]

**Best Poster Award** 

(a project mentored by Prof. Maneesh Agrawala at Stanford)

## **Teaching Experience**

- 2018 Teaching Assistant, Computer Vision: from Recognition to Geometry Instructor: Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang
- 2018 Teaching Assistant, Deep Learning for Computer Vision Instructor: Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang
- 2017 Teaching Assistant, Machine Learning Instructor: Prof. Hung-Yi Lee
- 2017 Teaching Assistant, Signals and Systems Instructor: Prof. Lin-Shan Lee
- 2016 Teaching Assistant, Electronics I Instructor: Prof. Liang-Hung Lu

## Honors and Awards

- 2020 Stanford Graduate Student Research Assistantship
- 2018 Phi Tau Phi Scholastic Honor Society Honorary Membership Graduated top 1% in NTU EECS Department
- 2014 2018 **Dean's List (5 times)** Top 5% GPA in each semester
  - 2018 Chien Shih-Liang Memorial Scholarship Given to two students in NTU EECS Department each year
  - 2017 Taiwan Ministry of Science and Technology Research Grant
  - 2017 Irving T. Ho Memorial Scholarship Given to one senior student in NTU EE Department each year

## **University Service**

## 

In light of the Black Lives Matter movement and anti-East Asian racism due to COVID-19, I co-lead an initiative at Stanford HCI Group to add readings that center on diversity, equity, and inclusion to the Ph.D. qualifying exam.

## 2020 - Present Graduate Residence Community Associate

I work with the Stanford Graduate Life Office and other community associates on promoting wellness and a sense of community in graduate residences with 1200+ students by coordinating social events that center on cultural diversity.

# Leadership Experience

#### 2016 - 2018 Founder, Makerspace of NTUEE &

My team and I founded a makerspace to assist students with their side projects. During COVID-19, our students developed a system that was deployed across the campus to automatically detect and track people's forehead temperatures.

2017 Chair, MakeNTU Makeathon &

My team and I launched the first nationwide makeathon in Taiwan with 200 participants and 70K USD in sponsorship. I led 60 students and cooperated with the Taipei City Government and 22 companies such as Google and Microsoft.

2016 - 2017 Director, Academic Department of NTUEE Student Association §

I led a team of 30 students to organize various university events, including research competitions, university fairs, and NTUEE+ alumni mixers for 800+ students in the EE department.

# Work Experience

- 2019 Mandatory Military Service, Taiwan.
- 2017 Software Engineering Intern, Cadence Design Systems, Inc., San Jose, CA.
  - o My code for Gate-Level and RTL circuit design automation and equivalence checking was checked-in for production.

### **Technical Skills**

Technical Skills Python, C++/C#, Matlab, Tensorflow, PyTorch, React, Javascript, CSS, HTML, Unity, OpenCV, Verilog, etc.

Languages English (fluent), Mandarin (native), Taiwanese Hokkien (native)